# Sammy Mahmoudi

Plano, TX
S linkedin.com/in/sammymahmoudi

sammymahmoudi@gmail.com
 github.com/BagelMaster5000

S sammymahmoudi.com

# Hello! I'm a Software Engineer specializing in C# and .NET.

I have significant, professional software engineering experience in C# and am constantly working on projects to learn new skills and meet new people. I code clean, communicate well, and am super friendly!

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: C# .NET 7.0 and ASP.NET
- Tools: Visual Studio 2022, Git Source Control (Fork GUI)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Blizzard Entertainment - December 2023 to Present

**Associate Software Engineer** 

#### Blizzard Entertainment - May 2023 to August 2023

Software Engineer Intern

- ASP.NET 7.0, C#, OAuth, GCP, GKE, RabbitMQ, Octopus Deploy, Kibana, GitHub, GitHub Actions, SwaggerUI
- Created a web service using C# and ASP.NET 7.0 to templatize, transform, style, and send Blizzard notification emails as a solo project for the Summer
- Utilized GitHub Actions, Octopus Deploy, and GKE to automatically build and deploy service in Google Cloud
- Learned and followed a new design pattern focused around volatility-based decomposition
- Designed and maintained unit tests to ensure functionality of newly-added and existing features

#### Lone Star Analysis - June 2022 to August 2022

### Software Engineer Intern

- .NET 5.0 MVVM, C#, XAML, WPF, SQLite, BitBucket
- Investigated viability of integrating TelerikUI into our application and presented my findings to company executives which resulted in the team successfully receiving licenses
- Participated in daily standups to communicate completed work, upcoming work, and roadblocks
- Received commendations on doing more than was expected and for my visual design sensibilities

#### Lone Star Analysis - June 2021 to August 2021

#### Software Engineer Intern

- React with Typescript, Django REST Framework, Python, Azure, Docker, PostgreSQL, BitBucket
- Learned and became proficient with a new tech stack within just 1 month
- Completed JIRA feature and bug tickets actively and created many tickets for bug reports and feature suggestions. Contributed equally to the project as the full-time software engineers
- Received commendations on learning quickly, writing clean code, and communicating clearly

#### Video Game Project Pizza Delivery Bagel - October 2020 to June 2022

Programmer, Designer, Artist, Sound Designer, Composer

- Programmed and designed a multi-platform, action-arcade video game in Unity with C#
- Developed game simultaneously for PC, Android, and Arcade Cabinet, and published game commercially on Steam and Google Play stores
- Included a variety of control options on each platform for accessibility (controller support, multiple control schemes, left and right-handed play)
- Utilized the Wwise audio engine for pitch and clip randomization, spacial audio, and simpler audio mixing
- Implemented a 3rd party terminal tool to allow executing debug commands in-game

# Video Game Project The Eaterer - March 2020 to July 2020

Programmer, Designer, Team Lead (Team of 2)

- Programmed and designed a 3D horror, action video game in Unity with C#
- Utilized an Excel spreadsheet to hold item info and used this data to spawn items throughout levels
- Compromised and eased tensions with co-developer following design disputes

#### Participated in 13+ Game Jam Challenges

• Programmed and designed video games in teams of 2-8 under tight time restrictions

# Game Jam <u>Grombcross</u> – August 2022

Programmer, Team Lead (Team of 5)

- Programmed a puzzle video game in WPF with .NET 6.0 MVVM, C#, and XAML
- Created a save system that saves and loads puzzle completion states and settings as a json file
- Created a puzzle generation system that generates nanogram puzzles from just a pair of bitmap images

#### Game Jam Project 9th Monday - October 2021

Programmer, Team Lead (Team of 8)

- Programmed an audio-only, horror, narrative game in Unity with C#
- Utilized a Windows speech-to-text API to allow for making story choices by speaking into a microphone
- Created a system to synchronize subtitles read from an Ink file with playback of dialog and sound effects in the Wwise audio engine

#### **EDUCATION**

### University of Texas at Dallas (GPA: 3.814) - December 2023

• Degree: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

#### **LEADERSHIP**

# <u>The Student Game Developer Association at UTD</u> – December 2021 to December 2023 Senior Officer, Treasurer

enior Officer, freasurer

- Assisted in planning and hosting events
- Created promotional materials such as the club tri-fold display and custom stickers

# The SpongeBob Club at UTD – September 2019 to February 2022

Founder, President

Hosted events, designed promotional posters, and managed a 120+ member Discord server

#### **SERVICE**

#### Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation - April 2022 to present

- Helped setup and assist guests at multiple charity auction events
- Assisted with miscellaneous office work such as preparing promotional materials and goodie bags